Abdelfatah Ashour

Mid-Level Frontend developer

Alexandria, Egypt +2 011 2097 4272

abdelfatahashour4@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdelfatah-ashour

Professional Summary

To seek and maintain full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills. Experienced working with teams to produce impactful, leading-edge websites that engage customers and deliver business results. Well-versed in design standards and user preferences.

Work Experience

Frontend Developer | Flowtechtics 7

Alexandria, Egypt | October 2021 - Present

- Implemented and deployed entries web applications more than +3 projects with React JS, Next JS, Redux, TypeScript and Firebase.
- Maintained high-level expertise in React state management strategies using Redux and Redux/toolkit.
- Created reusable React components for the date picker, dropdown, buttons, and input styles according to the provided designs.
- Implement custom hooks for parsing user agent, query URL, translation, protect routes, fetching API's.
- Integrated are third party packages like (Firebase cloud messaging & O2Auth & Charts JS).
- Handled errors in all cases to eb friendly for user as user experience.

Frontend Developer

Alexandria, Egypt | June 2022 - August 2022

- Joined with a team located in Cairo a remotely part-time. And I implemented +2 business requirements in project about virtual class online (joined at last 4 sprints and using agile methodology).
- Build custom components UI with Chakra UI and Tailwind CSS with animation, Implemented and integrated business requirements like Behaviors groups and Questions Group as a Components UI and API's using apollographql for CRUD operations.

Skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Sass
- React JS
- React Native (in progress)

- Next JS
- Redux
- @Redux/toolkit
- Webpack
- Jest
- @testing/Library
- GraphQL

- Socket-IO
- Git and GitHub
- OOP (Object-oriented Programming)
- FP (Functional Programming)
- SOLID
- Problem Solving

Projects

Krafttopia: (https://krafttopia.com)

• Overview: E-commerce and panels dashboard web application using React JS, Redux, Material UI, Firebase Cloud Messing and OAuth2.0.

Port-flash: (https://www.port-flash.online)

Overview: Transportation and logistics web application React JS, @Redux/toolkit and Material UI.

React-honey-hooks: (https://www.npmjs.com/package/react-honey-hooks)

- Source code: (https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/react-honey-hooks).
- Overview: React custom hooks.

Freedom Blogs: (http://express-x-you.vercel.app)

- Source code: (https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/express-x-you).
- Overview: Blog's web application using Next JS, Context API, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB.

Brakt: (https://brakt.vercel.app)

- Source code: (https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/brakt).
- Overview: Blog's web application using React JS, Redux, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB.

Sola: (https://sola.vercel.app)

- Source code: (https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/sola).
- Overview: Chat web application (Real-time) using React JS, Redux, Node JS, Express JS, MongoDB and Socket-IO.

Express-x-you: (http://express-x-you.vercel.app)

- Source code: (https://github.com/abdelfatah-ashour/express-x-you).
- Overview: E-commerce web application using Next JS, Redux, Node JS, Express JS and MongoDB.

Education

Bachelor's Degree, Faculty of Law

Alexandria University, October 2013 - May 2019

Personal Information

Birth of date: 16/12/1994

Military status: postponement

Languages:

Arabic: Native

English: Conversation